RANI COHEN

Information



Address Ramat Gan

Israel



Phone +972-54-7998393



Email

Aharonran7@gmail.com



Website

github.com/RoniRan542 roniran542.github.io/

Social



LinkedIn

ran-cohen-a0511441

ABOUT ME

A passionate software developer. I am a hardworking and highly motivated developer with practical experience in a wide variety of technology stack. I am a dedicated and internally motivated worker, creative thinker, and a problem-solver. With strong interpersonal skills, I am able to work independently while remaining a team player. In love with technology and science.



EXPERIENCE

09/2018 - 09/2021

THE HEBREW UNIVERSITY

Jerusalem

Web Developer

Developing independently a website for Gati's lab at the Hebrew University. Working with all aspects of the website life cycle.

01/2019 - 08/2021

THE HEBREW UNIVERSITY

Researcher & Lab manager

Jerusalem

Research in cognitive and brain sciences at HUJI while running a lab,

managing logistics and research plans.

08/2017 - 09/2018

BEIT PRAT

Jerusalem

Providing logistic planning and executing quality routines for a nonprofit

organization.

03/2016 - 09/2016

VATBOX Data cleansing

Hertzelia

Screening valuable data for the Vatbox software application.



EDUCATION

2022 - 2022INFINITYLABS BOOTCAMP

> Successfully completed intensive 8 months of software engineering training program, gaining practical development experience in C and C++ on linux environment, with focus on memory management, system programming, network and multi-threading. I also gained deep understanding of OOD and OOP, design patterns and data structures.

2018 - 2021

THE HEBREW UNIVERSITY - M.A

Masters in cognitive and brain sciences.

Thesis subject: learning from punishments and the interaction with mood

fluctuations (GBA: 89)

2015 - 2016JOHN BRYCE COLLEGE

Basics of Java programming, object-oriented concepts, as well as producing a server web application.

2011 - 2014

BAR ILAN UNIVERSITY - B.A

Bachelors degree in philosophy (major) and history (GBA: 90).

In addition, during this time, I took courses in logic, algorithmic thinking,

and web programming.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Proficiency in C and C++ as well as in JavaScript, Python and Java.
- Solid foundation in software development fundamentals: Data Structure, Design Patterns, Object-Oriented programming, System programming, Multithreading and algorithms.
- Experience working in a Linux environment and shell scripting.
- Experience in building Restful APIs with Flask and NodeJs.
- Prior experience as a front-end developer (HTML5 | CSS3 | JS | React | AngularJS).
- Good knowledge of integration, debugging & testing tools (Makefile | git | gdb | valgrind | vscode).
- Good background in databases and data manipulation tools (R | Matlab | MySQL | SQLite | sqlalchemy | MongoDB).

MILITARY SERVICE

Israel Defence Force, Infantry (Givaty platoon 2006-2009)

LANGUAGES

Hebrew: Native Language. English: Excellent.